Guide to the Adolph M. Foerster Collection, 1868-1923 CAM.FOER.2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Printed Music, II.
  - Opus 15 Fantasie for violin and piano, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    New York: J.O.V. Prochazka, 1885. 2 pages. pub. No. 200
  - Opus no. 1 Romance pour violon et piano, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, 1891. Score. 5 pages. Plate no. 1882
    - Opus no. 1 Romance pour violon et piano score, 1891 (Box 1, Item 17A)
    - Opus no. 1 Romance pour violon et piano violin (Box 1, Item 17b)
  - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen (Box 1, Folder 19)
    DarMStadt: Georg Thies. Score and parts. 4 pages. No. 1 Mondlicht, No. 2 Standchen Plate no. G27T.
    - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen score (Box 1, Item 19a)
    - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen 1st tenor (Box 1, Item 19b)
    - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen 2nd tenor (Box 1, Item 19c)
    - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen 1st bass (Box 1, Item 19d)
    - Opus 19 Zwei Lieder Fur vierstimmigen 2nd bass (Box 1, Item 19e)
  - Opus 21 Quartet (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt Nachfolger. 27 pages. Plate no 2929. The second page is missing. There are many corrections which are followed in the printed version.
    - Opus 21 Quartet score (Box 1, Item 21a)
    - Opus 21 Quartet violin (Box 1, Item 21b)
    - Opus 21 Quartet viola (Box 1, Item 21c)
    - Opus 21 Quartet cello (Box 1, Item 21d)
  - Opus 21 Erstes Quartet fur Violine, Bratsche, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt Nachfolger, 1888. score and parts. violoncello und Klavier. 25 pages. Plate no. 2929
    - Opus 21 Erstes Quartet fur Violine, Bratsche score (Box 1, Item 25a)
    - Opus 21 Erstes Quartet fur Violine, Bratsche violin (Box 1, Item 25b)
    - Opus 21 Erstes Quartet fur Violine, Bratsche viola (Box 1, Item 25c)
    - Opus 21 Erstes Quartet fur Violine, Bratsche cello (Box 1, Item 25d)
  - Opus 22 no. 1 The Bedouin's prayer, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Printed score. Columbus: Fitzgerald lithograph, 1887. 3 p. Agrees generally with the holograph
  - Opus 22 no. 1 The Bedouin's prayer, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro., 1888. 5 pages. After measure 32 it differs from the lithograph in that the tenor solo is altered and the time signature remains in 3/4. After measure 46 the tenor solo ends and for chorus only to the end. English and German.
  - Opus 22 no. 1 The Bedouin's prayer, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Brothers. 81 copies. Male chorus. 7 pages.
  - Opus 22 no. 2 June Song, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro, 1888. 40 copies.
  - Opus 28 Among flowers, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro., 1889. 18 copies. 32 pages. 1. Violets (Walton) 1. Sunflowers (Levee) 3. Love in a rosebush (H.V. Fallersleben) 4. For-get-me-not (Ritter) 5. The water-sprite (Ritter) 6. Among flowers (Ritter) 7. In blossom time (Coolbrith) 8. Old proverb (Moore) 9. Cradle song (Gilder) 10 On the wild rose tree (Gilder) 11. The young rose (Moore)
  - Opus 22 no. 2 June Song and Slumber, oh slumber, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Opus 22 no. 2 June Song (Box 3, Item 31A)
      Holograph. Mixed chorus. 1 page. This is the first pencil sketch and differs somewhat from the published score.
    - Slumber, oh slumber, May 6, 1888 (Box 3, Item 31B)
      holograph manuscript. Voice and piano. 2 pages.
  - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt score, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 43a)
      Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt, 1888. score. violoncello and piano. 1 page. Plate no. 2987. Proof copy #1 and part. Incomplete
    - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt cello, 1888 (Box 3, Item 43b)
  - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt fur Violoncello und Klavier, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt Nachfolger, 1888. 3 pages. Plate no. 2987 and part.
    - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt fur Violoncello und Klavier score, 1888 (Box 3, Item 44a)
    - Opus 24 Ein Albumblatt fur Violoncello und Klavier cello (Box 3, Item 44b)
  - Opus 26 Novelette fur Violine and Klavier (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr., 1890. 6 pages. Plate no. G29T
    - Opus 26 Novelette fur Violine and Klavier score, 1890 (Box 3, Item 48a)
    - Opus 26 Novelette fur Violine and Klavier violin, 1890 (Box 3, Item 48b)
  - Opus 29 Trio, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Berlin: C.A. Challier & Co., 1893. 42 pages. Plate no. 3485. Proof copy with notation at the bottom of the first page "The red are the errors in the 1st proof, the black in the second, and the blue in the third." The printer is C.G. Rode and bears the above date.
    - Opus 29 Trio score, 1893 (Box 3, Item 53a)
    - Opus 29 Trio violin, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 53b)
    - Opus 29 Trio cello, 1893 (Box 3, Item 53c)
  - Opus 29 Trio fur Klavier, Violine und Violoncello (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Berlin: C.A. Challier & Co. score and parts. Plate no. 3485. " The printer is C.G. Rode and bears the above date.
    - Opus 29 Trio fur Klavier, Violine und Violoncello score (Box 3, Item 54a)
    - Opus 29 Trio fur Klavier, Violine und Violoncello violin (Box 3, Item 54b)
    - Opus 29 Trio fur Klavier, Violine und Violoncello cello (Box 3, Item 54c)
  - Opus 32 Festival March, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    New York: Carl Fisher. Score and parts. 28 pages. Plate no. 39 Two scores are bound and have a list of performances pasted onto the inside cover leaf: Both contain heading, "Foerster's personal copy": collection has only string parts: Personal copy scanned.
    - Opus 32 Festival March: score, 1915 (Box 4, Item 63a)
    - Opus 32 Festival March: 1st Violin, 1915 (Box 4, Item 63b)
    - Opus 32 Festival March: 2nd violin, 1915 (Box 4, Item 63c)
    - Opus 32 Festival March: viola, 1918 (Box 4, Item 63d)
    - Opus 32 Festival March: cello, 1918 (Box 4, Item 63e)
    - Opus 32 Festival March: bass, 1918 (Box 4, Item 63f)
  - Opus 32 Festival March (Box 5, Folder 62)
    Proof score. 28 pages. Plate no. 39. Pages 31-35 missing.
  - Opus 34 Two Songs, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 67, Item 67b)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. I saw thee weep 2. Adoration. Plate no. 4
  - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 1 Novelette, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Plate no. 21119
    - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 1 Novelette: score, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 70, Item 70a)
    - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 1 Novelette: violin, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 70, Item 70b)
  - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 3 Duo, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    Leipzig: Breitkopf & Hartel. Pl no. 21121
    - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 3 Duo: score, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 71, Item 71a)
    - Opus 36 Suite fur Violine und Klavier no. 3 Duo: violin, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 71, Item 71b)
  - Opus 38 Twelve fantasy pieces for the pianoforte, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber, 1894. 2. Sylvan spirits 3. Evenings bells 4. Canon 5. The sea 6. Harlequin. Part II 7. Pretty Marie Part III 10. Prelude 11. Mazurka 12. Homage to Rubinstein. four complete copies and one additional incomplete copy of part III, one complete copy and one partial copy of part two, and one incomplete copy of part one.
  - Opus Cavatina No. 1, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth. Score and parts. Plate no. 51: retitled "Devotion" @1922
    - Opus Cavatina No. 1: score, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 79, Item 79a)
    - Opus Cavatina No. 1: cello, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 79, Item 79b)
  - Opus 42 no. 1 Autumn leaves, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    Milwaukee: Rohlfing Sons Music Co. Voice and piano. Plate no. 731.
  - Opus 42 no. 2 Little wild rose, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    Milwaukee: Rohlfing Sons Music Co., Voice and piano. Plate no. 731
  - Opus 43 Dedication march, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    New York: Breitkopf & Hartel, 1899. Orchestra score. Inside cover page has program notes from 1920.
  - Opus 43 Dedication march, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    New York: Breitkopf & Hartel. Orchestra score and parts. Found in orange linen cover. In excess of 5 complete sets.
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: score, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91a)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st flute, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91b)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd flute, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91c)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st oboe, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91d)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd oboe, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91e)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st clarinet, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91f)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd clarinet, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91h)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st basson, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91h)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd bassoon, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91i)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: first horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91j)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91k)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91l)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 4th horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91m)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91n)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91o)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91p)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91q)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91r)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91s)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tuba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91t)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tria, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91u)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: cassa-piatta, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91r)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tympani, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91w)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st violin, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91x)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd violin, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91y)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: viola, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91z)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: cello, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91aa)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: bass, 1899 (Box 6, Item 91bb)
  - Opus 43 Dedication march, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    New York: Breitkopf & Hartel. Orchestra score and parts. Revision copy: primarily of bowling, phrasing, temp and dynamics. An additional note in German indicates that from the 3rd measure on page 14 to the 5th measure on page 17 can be omitted without any noticeable break. The parts are also corrected.
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: score, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92a)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st violin, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92b)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd violin, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92c)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: viola, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92d)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: cello, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92e)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: bass, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92f)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st flute, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92g)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd flute, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92h)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st oboe, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92i)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd oboe, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92j)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st clarinet, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92k)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd clarinet, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92l)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st bassoon, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92m)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd bassoon, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92n)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92o)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92p)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92q)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 4th horn, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92r)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92s)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92t)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd tromba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92v)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 1st trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92v)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 2nd trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92w)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: 3rd trombone, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92x)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tuba, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92y)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: tria, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92z)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: Cassa-Piatti, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92aa)
    - Opus 43 Dedication march: Tympani, 1899 (Box 6, Item 92bb)
  - Opus 43 (sic 45) no. 1 The Grecian isles, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. 5 pages. Plate no. 2417.
  - Opus 45 no. 2 She walks in beauty, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 4 pages. Plate no. 2418.
  - Opus 45 no. 3 Shepherd's lament, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 4 pages. Plate no. 2419
  - Opus 46 Suite for the piano, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 4 pages. 1. Prelude 2. Waltz 3. Intermezzo 4. Finale Homage to Brahms. Plate no. 5
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust (Box 7, Folder 115)
    Orchestra score proof. 36 pages. Plate no. 37. Corrections made in red ink. First proof.
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust (Box 7, Folder 116)
    Orchestra proof. Plate no. 37. Last page missing, a few corrections. Second proof.: includes several parts and extra score pp.(unrealated to the complete copy?)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: score (Box 7, Item 116a)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: tuba (Box 7, Item 116b)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 3rd trombone (Box 7, Item 116c)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: ex.pp (Box 7, Item 116d)
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    New York: Carl Fischer, 1915. Orchestra score. Plate no. 37. This composition was a prize work of the Art Society of Pittsburgh and received its initial performance by the Pittsburgh Orchestra in December 1898, under Victor Herbert. The inside cover leaf has a program clipping plus a typewritten page with an explanation of the motives. On the last page is a sheet of MS paper with the motives written out. This gives an important guide to the composition.
  - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    Proof score and parts. Plate no. 38. Correction in red ink. Printer's stamp is C.G. Rode. No clue as to publisher.
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: score, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108a)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: harp, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108b)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: 1st bassoon, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108c)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: 2nd violin, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108d)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: viola, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108e)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: cello, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108f)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: bass, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108g)
    - Opus 47 Second Suite Proof: 1st and 2nd trombone, 1915 (Box 8, Item 108h)
  - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Folder 118)
    New York: Carl Fischer. 3 copies. Plate no. 37.
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: score, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118a)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st violin, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118b)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd violin, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118c)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: cello, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118e)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: bass, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118f)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st flute, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118g)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd flute, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118h)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st oboe, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118i)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd oboe, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118j)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st clarinet, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118k)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd clarinet, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118l)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st bassoon, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118m)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd bassoon, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118n)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st horn, 118o (Box 8, 9, Item 118o)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd horn, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118p)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 3rd horn, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118q)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 4th horn, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118r)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st trumpet, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118s)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd trumpet, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118t)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 1st trombone, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118u)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 2nd trombone, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118v)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: 3rd trombone, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118w)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: tuba, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118x)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: harp, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118y)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: tympani, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118z)
    - Opus 48 Prelude to Goethe's Faust: beck, 1915 (Box 8, 9, Item 118aa)
  - Opus 51 Call to charon, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Voice and piano. 14 pages. 4 copies. Plate no. 53.
  - Opus 51 Call to charon, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 128)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Voice and orchestra. 33 pages. plate no. 52. Inside cover page has a program clipping showing the first performance was at Philadelphia in 1925. Score bound in orange linen cover with gamble hinge. Also 3 copies unbound
  - Opus 53 Album of lyrics: Proof, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    Proof score. 1. Nature and song 3. Dreaming 6. Sleeping love 7. Stars everywhere 8. Suggestion 10. Farewell (incomplete). Plate no. 16. Publisher not listed but printers stamp on first page is Roder. Incomplete
  - Opus 54 no. 4 Love's philosophy, 1900 (Box 10, Folder 147)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro.
  - Opus 55 no. 5 Oh, fairest of the rural maids, 1900 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - Opus 57 Six Songs, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 150)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. Unceasing love (Lytton) 2. The Fir Tree (Heine) 3. A wondrous thing't must be (Redwitz) 4. Early spring (Goethe) 5. Forester's song (Shakespeare) 6. Spring is here (Schafer)
  - Opus 57 Six Songs, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    Holograph score. Plate no. 20. Revised edition.
  - Opus 58 no. 1 Lead us heavenly father and Opus 58 no. 2 The spring-tide hour, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Opus 58 no. 2 The spring-tide hour, 1903 (Box 10, Item 152b)
    - Opus 58 no. 1 Lead us heavenly father, 1903 (Box 10, Item 152a)
      Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Plate no. 8.
  - Opus 58 no. 1 Lead us heavenly father, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - Opus 58 no. 3 Ave Verum, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 154)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Chorus. plate no. 10
  - Opus 58 no. 4 Out of the deep, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 155)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. solo, chorus, and organ. plate no. 11
  - Opus 58 no. 5 Christ is our cornerstone, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. plate no. 12
  - Opus 60 Tristram and Iseult, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 161)
    Boston: Oliver Diston. Plate no. 680.
  - Opus 61 Trio-Serenade, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 165)
    New York: Carl Fisher. Score and parts. plate no. 18426.
    - Opus 61 Trio-Serenade: score, 1915 (Box 10, Item 165a)
    - Opus 61 Trio-Serenade: violin, 1915 (Box 10, Item 165b)
    - Opus 61 Trio-Serenade: cello, 1915 (Box 10, Item 165c)
  - Opus 63 Greek love songs, cycle, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 169)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. Time's revenges 2. Love in the wine 3. The light of the flame 6. Purity of love 7. Kiss within the cup 8. After the revel 9. Love aflame. 4 copies and one page of proof with corrections.
  - Opus 64 Garland of songs part 1, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 171)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. Song of the soul (Golder) 2. The starless night (Golder) 3. The Starlit night (Golder) 4. The robin's lullaby (Golder) 5. 'Tis the last rose of summer (Moore) 6. The silent sea (Coleridge). Plate no. 13
  - Opus 64 Garland of songs part 2, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 172)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 7. To the beloved (Roxby) 8. Love me if I live (Cornwall) 9. Heart Song (Deane) 10. Love alone (Moore) 11. Enraptured (Byron) 12 Sun of the sleepless (Byron). Plate no. 14
  - Opus 64 Garland of songs proof (Box 10, Folder 173)
    Proof score. Voice and piano. Plate no. 13 & 14. Complete proof copy with some extra pages. One correction in pencil and another in red ink. Parts 1 & 2.
  - Opus 65 Four love songs, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 175)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Score: voice and piano. 1. I love thee (Hood) 2. Love thee, dearest? (Moore) 3. Love's litany (Bruce) 4. To see thee, to love thee (Moore). Plate no. 17. 3 copies.
  - Opus 68 no. 1 Sunday in May, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber & Bro. Male chorus. plate no. 20. 19 copies.
  - Opus 68 no. 1 Sunday in May: proof, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 180)
    Proof copy. Male chorus. Plate no. 20. Marked as revised copy.
  - Opus 68 no. 2 The voyagers, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 181)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Male Chorus. Plate no. 22
  - Opus 68 No. 3 Rhine journey and Opus 68 No. 4 Summer Night, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Male chorus. Plate no. 25
    - Opus 68 no. 3 Rhine journey, 1910 (Box 12, Item 182A)
    - Opus 68 no. 4 Summer night, 1910 (Box 12, Item 182B)
  - Opus 69 Second album of lyrics, part 1, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 183)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. Twilight reverie (Byron) 2. Swan song (Ballestrem) 3. Love (Byron) 4. Absolved (Reinick) 5. Midnight reverie (A.M. Foerster) 6. A tear (Moore) 7. Withered flowers (E. Foerster) 8. Where e'ever I am (Heine) 9. If thou must depart (Arnold) 2 copies
  - Opus 69 Second album of lyrics, part 2, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 184)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. At night (Moore) 2. Row gently, my gondolier (Moore) 3. Longing (Moore) 4. Through the wind (Reinick) 5. In March (Hepp) 6. Inquiry (Hepp) 7. Evening love song (Lanier) Plate no. 24
  - Opus 72 Enslaved. A blight has fallen, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 186)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Voice and piano.
  - Opus 74 Two songs, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. The Indian maid (Moore) 2. Calm by thy sleep (Moore) Plate no. 29
  - Opus 75 Two songs, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. 1. Alone (c. Young) 2. Here sleep the bard (Moore) Plate no. 30
  - Opus 76 no. 1 Song of the woods, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    New York: Carl Fisher. Plate no. 14858. 3 copies.
  - Opus 76 no. 3 An evening song, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    New York: Carl Fisher. Plate no 14856. This poem by Schafer is the same one used in opus 54 no. 3 but is given different treatment here. 3 copies.
  - Opus 77 Nocturne-epigram, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    Pittsburg: H. Kleber. Plate no. 31
  - Opus 80 Love visions, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 202)
    Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth, Jr. Score. Voice and piano.
  - Opus 80 Love visions, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    Score and parts. Leipzig: Fritz Schuberth. Plate no. 44
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: score, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203a)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st violin, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203b)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd violin, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203c)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: viola, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203d)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: cello, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203e)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: bass, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203f)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st flute, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203g)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd oboe, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203h)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st oboe, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203i)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd flute, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203j)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st clarinet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203k)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd bassoon, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203l)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st bassoon, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203m)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd clarinet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203n)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203o)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd trumpet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203p)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st trumpet, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203q)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd horn, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203r)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 1st trombone, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203s)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: 2nd trombone, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203t)
    - Opus 80 Love Visions: tympani, 1922 (Box 12, Item 203u)